insidepulse.com 2014-12-16

# Inside Pulse Privacy

Thank you for visiting Inside Pulse or one of our affiliate sites. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us, and with that in mind we have devised this notice to fully disclose our online information practices. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for Inside Pulse – what information we gather, how we use it and how to correct or change it.

**Third Party Advertising**

We use various advertising companies to serve ads and collect information when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site, other sites and other forms of media about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp).

**Third Party Cookies**  
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique “cookie” on your browser.

**Information Collection And Use**  
At some Inside Pulse sites, it is possible to order products, enter contests, vote in polls, subscribe to newsletters, or participate in online forums or communities. In these areas, the user often must provide personally identifiable information, including but not limited to: name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, credit card information, and information about your interests in and use of various products, programs, and services.

In addition to direct submission of personal information, Inside Pulse can collect certain non-personally identifiable information when you visit many of our web pages such as the type of browser you are using (Internet Explorer Netscape, etc), the type of operating system you are using, (Linux, Windows, etc) and the domain name of your Internet service provider (America Online, MSN, etc).

**How We Use the Information**  
The information you provide about yourself is used by Inside Pulse to fulfill your requests for our products, programs, and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, and to offer you other products, programs or services that we believe may be of interest to you.

Sometimes, Inside Pulse will make use of this information to communicate with users. Some examples of this include sending notice to contest winners, or notifying users about changes made to subscriber agreements, fulfilling a request for an online newsletter, or other such activities.

The information collected in connection with online forums and communities is used to provide an interactive experience. This information is utilized to facilitate participation in these online forums and communities and, from time to time, to offer users products, programs, or services.

On occasion, Inside Pulse may use the non-personally identifiable information collected to improve the design and content of Inside Pulse and its sites and to enable us to personalize the overall experience of each individual visitor. This information may also be used to analyze site usage, as well as to offer visitors products, programs, or services.

We will disclose information we maintain when required to do so by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request.

Agents and contractors of Inside Pulse who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with the privacy policy by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for Inside Pulse.

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this privacy policy notice. Inadvertent disclosures may result, for example, when third parties misrepresent their identities in asking the site for access to personally identifiable information about themselves for purposes of correcting possible factual errors in the data.

Inside Pulse sites will not use or transfer personally identifiable information provided to us in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you with an opportunity to opt out of these unrelated uses.

**Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites and Sponsors**  
Inside Pulse or its affiliates sometimes contain links to partners, advertisers and third party Internet sites and services who may collect data in connection with sweepstakes, promotions, e-commerce, etc. Inside Pulse cannot control what happens to information provided by users to these entities. They each have separate privacy and data collection practices, independent of Inside Pulse.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are text files placed in the users’ computer’s browser to store your preferences. On their own, cookies do not provide your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information. But if the user provides that information, for example, by registering at Inside Pulse or an affiliate site, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

Inside Pulse uses cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and offerings on the sites. For example, cookies could be used to personalize the users’ experience at our web pages (such as to already be logged in at a message board), save your password in password-protected areas, and enable you to use shopping carts on our sites. Cookies may also be used to offer products, programs, or services to the user.

**Traffic Monitoring**  
Inside Pulse uses server logs and a public tracking system, as well as data provided by the Tribal Fusion ad serving software, to analyze traffic to this web site. Our system does not create individual profiles for visitors but does log IP visitor IP addresses for security reasons..

**Contact**

If there are any additional privacy concerns, don’t hesitate to e-mail us and any questions will be answered to the best of our ability. All of our contact information can be found [here](http://www.inside%20pulse/about_us/contact_us).
